{
  "reference_number": "7285",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "We need ambitious action now"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": "Net Zero Emissions - Net zero emissions across all greenhouse gases by 2050",
      "answer_index": 1,
      "notes": "Because agriculture contributes 50% of emissions and ethane is a significant player, we can't ignore this and need to research our\n\n response urgently"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": "Domestic emissions reductions only (including from new forest planting)",
      "answer_index": 7,
      "notes": "Preferably but which ever option gives the best global result in reduction of emissions, as the problem is global and we are not in a\n protected bubble in NZ."
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "No",
      "answer_index": 8,
      "notes": "It shouldn't be weakened. A change in government must not allow reversal of initiatives that will take time to show benefit- long term\n\n fixes dont always show immediate results"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "Yes - the third emissions budget should be able to be changed but only when the subsequent budget is set",
      "answer_index": 4,
      "notes": "Difficult to predict the issues for 5 years ,so some flexibility in prioritising is needed, as long as weakening the targets are not the\n intention"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Investment in low carbon transport infrastructure Reduction in waste generation eg packaging, particularly non reusable packaging\n\nSubsidisation of glass and soft plastic recycling businesses Incentives for people who invest in solar power Reworking of local\nlegislation to encourage smaller homes and higher density"
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The Government needs to be accountable to an independent body who isn't influenced by 3 yrly elections"
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": "Advising the Government on policy settings in the NZ ETS",
      "answer_index": 6,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "Conflicts of interest must be absolutely absent"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": null
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Thank you for the opportunity to have some input. I feel strongly about global warming and that NZ can only benefit from taking a lead\n\nglobally in emission reduction. Short term costs will give long term advantage in to the future. I am a Nurse and am dismayed at the\nshort term view , and token gestures that hospitals take towards waste reduction. An example of this immoral approach to global\n\nresources : single use stainless steel scissors and forceps which are imported from third world ? India, used once, then discarded. In\nthe past hospitals have had larger sterilisation services and good quality scissors etc have been autoclaved and reused. The\neconomics of this situation is immoral and happens in many areas of business- and points to reasons why we are in our current\n\nenvironmental predicament"
    }
  ]
}
